A Guide to the Judy Project: African American History at Richmond Hill research papers, 2019-2022
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Judy Project: African American History at Richmond Hill research papers, 2019-2022
Library of Virginia
54022
2.7 cubic feet (6 boxes) and 1 website.
Pam Smith
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Pam Smith, Falls Church, Virginia.
Biographical Information
The Richard Adams House was constructed about 1790 by Richard Adams (d. 1802) on property purchased from the John Coles family. The property was inherited by his son, Richard Adams, Jr. (1760-1817), and later by Richard Adams, III, who sold it to Loftin N. Ellett in 1825. Ellett died in 1865 and his executors sold the house in 1866 to Bishop John McGill of the Roman Catholic Diocese of Richmond. The Adams-Taylor House was built in 1812 for James Smith on property owned by Richard Adams, Jr. When Smith died in 1817, the house was purchased by Jacob Galt Ege. The house was sold by court order in 1833 to William Palmer (1801-1870). Palmer sold the house to William Taylor in 1859, and Taylor enlarged the house that year. Taylor then sold the house to Richard A. Wilkins in 1860. The Richmond Diocese purchased the house from Wilkins in 1866 and requested that the Sisters of the Visitation establish a monastery and girls' school known as Monte Maria at the Richard Adams House. The Adams-Taylor House became part of the campus in 1880. Later construction on campus included the demolition of the Richard Adams House about 1929. By the 1980s, the Sisters of the Visitation planned to relocate to Hanover County, Virginia. An ecumenical group called Richmond Hill purchased the property in 1987 and operates the site as an urban retreat center.
Scope and Content
The Judy Project: African American History at Richmond Hill research papers, September 2019-November 2022, contains research materials gathered by Pam Smith to document the lives and dwelling of enslaved persons at the Richard Adams House and the Adams-Taylor House properties in Richmond, Virginia, now known as Richmond Hill. Papers include articles, birth records, census records and slave schedules, death records, deeds, insurance policies, marriage records, personal correspondence, poems, reports, wills, and related Richmond Hill programming and exhibit materials, as well as the website.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged
Series I: Introduction
Series II: Dwelling
Series III: Richmond Hill--Reports
Series IV: Neighborhood reports
Series V: Coles-Adams
Series VI: Ellett
Series VII: Ege-Palmer-Taylor
Series VIII: Wilkins-Judy and her enslavers
Series IX: Sister Mildred Dolbear
Series X: Descendants-Bijan Bayne
Series XI: Descendants
Series XII: Research Assistance
Series XIII: Davenport
Series XIV: General
Series XV: Articles
Contents List
- Introduction (Box 1)
  Introduction contains information on the Judy Project exhibition, including information on owners of the property at what is now Richmond Hill; slavery and enslaved persons at Richmond Hill; and information on the dwellings located at Richmond Hill.
  - A Word About This Research (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Library of Virginia deed of gift, 12 November 2022 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Why are we doing this? What's it about? Who benefits? (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Biographies of property owners at what is now Richmond Hill (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Slavery in Virginia and slave traders in Richmond (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Villas on the Hill: Richmond's Richard Adams and Adams-Taylor Houses, in Urban Scale Richmond website, 28 June 2019 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Land ownership of Richmond Hill (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Enslavement at Richmond Hill property (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - William F. Butler records (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Black Lives on Richmond Hill: a research project (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Colonial wills of Henrico County, Virginia, 1737-1781, slave index: some names at Richmond Hill (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Notes (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Dwelling (Box 1)
  Dwelling contains information on the archaeological, architectural, and historical research documenting the dwelling of enslaved persons at Richmond Hill, including emails, insurance policies, itineraries, maps, photographs, reports, surveys, and other documents.
  - Took shed--Hermitage (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Jobie Hill--architect (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Rehabilitation of the dwelling of enslaved persons (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Mutual Assurance Society policies (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Mutual Assurance Society (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Doug Sanford emails, re: Mutual Assurance Society database, 26 February 2022 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Historic Building Survey (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Richard Adams House in Houses of Old Richmond, by Mary Wingfield Scott, pp. 12-15 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Enslaved craftsmen (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - For a Black Man Hired to Undo a Confederate Legacy, It Has Not Been Easy, New York Times, 17 April 2022 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Keast and Hood Structural Assessment Report, pp. 62-63, 18 December 2017 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Biblical references to dwellings (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Historic maps (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Unearthing Buried Stories exhibit, The Judy Project, Juneteenth 2022 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Richmond Hill--Reports (Box 1)
  Richmond Hill--Reports contains archaeological and architectural assessments of the dwelling of enslaved persons at Richmond Hill.
  - Richmond Hill Slave House, by Jobie Hill, Historic Preservation Architect, Founder of Saving Slave Houses, 15 January 2020 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Archaeological Assessment of Cultural Deposits Beneath a Damaged Walkway at Richmond Hill, City of Richmond, Virginia: Management Summary, by Tim Roberts (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Virginia Department of Historic Resources archaeological site record, 10 August 2021 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Report on Artifact Cataloguing and General Assemblage Analysis, Richmond Hill 2020 Walkway Project, by Carole Nash, Ph.D., James Madison University, 3 June 2021 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Richmond Hill Slave House Structural Assessment Report, by Springpoint Structural LLC, 4 April 2022 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Architectural Evaluation of the Richmodn Hill Brick Outbuilding, by Douglas W. Sanford, Virginia Slave Housing Project, May 2022 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Further Investigation of the Richmond Hill Kitchen-Quarter and Its Relation to the Property's Brick Boundary Walls, by Douglas W. Sanford, Virginia Slave Housing Project, 26 October 2022 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Draft update by Tim Roberts, 3 November 2022 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Seeking the Unknown: A Ground-Penetrating Radar Survey of the Quarters and the Cemetery at Richmond Hills, Richmond, VA, by Paul S. Martin, Martin Archaeology Consulting, 10 March 2023 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Email correspondence with Gibson Worsham, architect at Glave and Holmes, 8, 11 April 2022 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Short form agreement for services with Baskervill, architect (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Neighborhood Reports (Box 1-2)
  Neighborhood Reports contains articles, letters, maps, reports, wills, and other documents concerning the history of Richmond, Virginia, including significant African American sites.
  - Preliminary Archaeological Investigation of the Lumpkin's Jail Site (44HE1043) Richmond, Virginia, prepared for the City of Richmond by Matthew R. Laird, Ph.D. James River Institute for Archaeology, May 2006 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Sentinal on the Hill: Monte Maria and One Hundred Years, pp. 24, 139-143; also tombstone for Earsell H. Jeffers (1897-1985) (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Ann Carrington House (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Battle of Bloody Run (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Letter from Pam Smith, historian at Richmond Hill, to Congressman Donald McEachin regarding teh African American Burial Grounds Network Act, 22 October 2020 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Stoney Aims to Lease Shockoe Bottom Site linked to Slavery, Richmond Times-Dispatch, 20 September 2019 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Elizabeth Van Lew (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Elizabeth Draper Mitchell and Maggie Lena Walker (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Patrick Henry's will (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Association of Counties regions (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Preliminary History of the Lumpkin's Jail Property (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Giving the Wall: A Tour of African American Historical Sites in Richmond, Virginia, 1619-1860, by Clifford R. Dickinson, The Museum of the Confederacy, Richmond, 18 March 2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Coles-Adams (Box 2)
  Coles-Adams contains records regarding members of the Coles and Adams families that owned the properties and were enslavers. Also includes records of enslaved persons at the Coles and Adams properties.
  - Enniscorthy--Coles family home in Albemarle County (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - John Coles (1705-1747) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - John Coles will, Albemarle County, 1791 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - John Coles estate inventory and appraisal, Chesterfield County, 1816-1817 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - John Coles petition (from Race and Slavery Petitions Project), 1843 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Walter Coles ca. 1690-1740 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Walter Coles (b. 1910) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Walter Coles email, 18 May 2022 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Coles Hill and Virginia Uranium, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Isaac Coles (1747-1813) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Isaac Coles petition (from Race and Slavery Petitions Project), 1838-1839 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - John Coles II (1745-1808) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Coles family (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Edward Coles (1786-1868) (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Richard Adams House (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Richard Adams' ship records--New York Historical Society (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Richard Adams papers--correspondence, receipts, accounts, indenture, will, 1763-1800 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Documents relating to Richard Adams and house (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Adams family papers at the Virginia Historical Society (Virginia Museum of History and Culture) (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Richard Adams (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Brazilde Romo records (Free Black) (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Runaway ad for Ralph Chillingsworth, Virginia Gazette, 29 December 1775 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Richard Adams census record, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Richard Adams petition (from the Race and Slavery Petitions Project), 1842 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Abstracts of deeds for purchase of enslaved persons and property--Henrico County, 1750-1795 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Ebenezer Adams, Richard Adams, John Adams, Mary Griffin Adams (Minge) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Thomas Adams--will and correspondence regarding enslaved persons, 1769-1785 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Ellett (Box 2-3)
  Ellett contains records regarding members of the Loftin N. Ellett family that purchased the Richard Adams House and were enslavers. Also includes records of persons enslaved by Ellett. Records also contain information of African American families with the last name of Ellett.
  - Loftin Newman Ellett (1797-1865) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Loftin Newman Ellett--enslaved person birth records, 1852-1858 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - James B. Ellett (1789-1856) (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - James T. Ellett petition (from Race and Slavery Petitions Project), 1859 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Mary M. Ellett (Sherman) records (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Andrew Lewis Ellett census records, 1870, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Ann R. Garrett--enslaver of Robert?--census records and slave schedules, 1850, 1860 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Samuel Ellett (1810-1894) (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Tazewell Ellett (1856-1914) (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Tazewell Ellett registration card, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Emeline Ellett and family records, 1860-1940 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Dabney Ellett and Martha Ellett records, 1870-1920 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - David Ellett census record, 1870 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Walthall family records, 1855, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Loftin Ellett slave schedules, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Bond of complaint filed by Loftin Ellet, 1860 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Presidential pardon for Loftin Ellett, 30 June 1865 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Elletts in 1870 census and Elletts in 1866 city directory (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Randolph Ellett (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Andrew Lewis Ellett (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cordey Ellett (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dabney Ellett and family (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Loftin Ellett will recorded 18 December 1865 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Andrew Lewis Ellett records. 1865-1919 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Ellett descendants--Sarah Herguner email, 13 November 2020 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Pleasants Dabney Ellett and family records, 1880-1910 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Robert Ellett (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Mary Ellett and family (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Ege-Palmer-Taylor (Box 3)
  Ege-Palmer-Taylor contains records regarding members of the Ege, Palmer, and Taylor families that purchased what became known as the Adams-Taylor House and were enslavers. Also includes records of persons enslaved by the Ege, Palmer, and Taylor families. Records also contain information of African American families with the last name of Palmer.
  - Ege family genealogy (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Ege mansion (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Jacob Galt Ege (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Enders family (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - William Palmer (1801-1870) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - William Palmer census records, 1850, 1860, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - William H. Palmer (1835-1926) (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Palmer family (African American) (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - William S. Taylor (1810-1904) and family (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - James D. Taylor and family (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - James Smith will, 23 December 1850 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Wilkins--Judy and her enslavers (Box 3-4)
  Wilkins--Judy and her enslavers contains records regarding members of the Wilkins family that purchased what became known as the Adams-Taylor House and were enslavers. Also includes records of persons enslaved by the Wilkins family, including Judy, for whom the Judy Project is named. Records also contain information of African American families with the last name of Wilkins.
  - Notes (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - John Limbrey Wilkins (1710-1747) (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Edmund Wilkins and family (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - William Wyche Wilkins (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Douglas Wilkins and family (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - John Douglas Wilkins and family (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Richard Wilkins (1815-1877) and family (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - William Minge Wilkins (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Richard Wilkins (1849-1925) (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Mary Griffin Wilkins (Ervin) (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Molly Ervin Inge (Crown) (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Minge-Inge family (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Wilkins, Inge, Ross, Pattilo, and Kimball families (African American) (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Margaret Adams Erwin (Inge) (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Benjamin H. Wilkins (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Margaret Winston Adams and Mary Griffin Minge (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Margaret Adams Minge Wilkins and Mary Griffin Wilkins (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Search for an Old House in Virginia, Virginia Episcopalian, January 1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Judy (Wilkins) for whom the Judy Project is named (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Thomas Tom Wilkins and family (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Ned Wilkins and Laura Seward Wilkins (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Wilkins family (African American) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Berry Hill plantation--Sankofa's Slavery Data Collection (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Lucretia Brown (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Sister Mildred Dolbear (Box 4)
  Sister Mildred Dolbear contains biographical and genealogical information on Sister Mildred Dolbear, a nun at Monte Maria, the predecessor institution to Richmond Hill. Includes information on racial identity in Catholic organizations and interracial familial relationships.
  - Sister Mildred Dolbear records (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Father and paternal grandparents (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Mother and maternal grandparents (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - You Could Do the Irish Jig, But Anything African Was Taboo: Black Nuns, Contested Memories, and the 20th Century Struggle to Desegregate U.S. Catholic Religious Life, by Shannen Dee Williams, Journal of African American History, volume 102, number 2, Spring 2017 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Robb family petition (Race and Slavery Petitions Project), 1829 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Unlocking the Closet of Secrets: Slavery in the City of Mobile, Alabama (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Schmidt, Robb, Dolbear (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Bryant (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Robb's Folly: Lost Plazzo of the Garden District, Preservation Resource Center of New Orleans, 7 April 2017 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Descendants-Bijan Bayne (Box 4)
  Descendants-Bijan Bayne contains information on the Avent, Shaw, and Wilkins families that descended from enslaved persons enslaved by the Wilkins family highlighting the ancestry of Bijan Bayne. Papers include census records and slave schedules, city directory entries, emails, genealogical records, marriage records, notes, and photographs.
  - Gerald Roer Shaw (father) and Geneva Bertha Halstead (grandmother) (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Bijan C. Bayne (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - AfriGeneas Genealogy and History Forum Archive and AfriGeneas Slave Research Forum, 2002-2003 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Wilkins family (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Bijan Bayne email correspondence with Pam Smith, September-October 2021 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Notes (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Gerald Shaw (b. 1934) (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Photograph--Shaw family(?) (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Wilkins-Avent-Shaw family (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Descendants (Box 4-5)
  Descendants contains articles, notes, and educational rubrics regarding descendants of enslaved persons and reparations, as well as census records, death records, emails, genealogical records, notes, and wills on the Adams, Brown, Early, Holmes, and Peoples families. Includes an open letter to the director of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts regarding the site where the Robert E. Lee Monument stood expressing concerns over the site's future.
  - Engaging Descendant Communities in the Interpretation of Slavery at Museums and Historic Sites: A Rubric of Best Practices Established by the National Summit on Teaching Slavery, National Trust for Historic Preservation and African American Cultural Heritage Action Fund, 15 October 2018 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - A Nation Built on the Back of Slavery and Racism, Yes! magazine, Summer 2015 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Reparations, 6 October 2021 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - James Madison's Plantation Vowed to Share Power with Black Descendants. Then Things Blew Up. Washington Post, 22 April 2022 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Montpelier Foundation Chooses New Leaders for Presidential Home, Culpeper Star Exponent, 25 May 2022 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Supreme Court to Consider Virginia Uranium Case that Divides a Rural County, Washington Post--Coles family, Pittsylvania County, 4 November 2018 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Notes (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Email correspondence--Helena Holmes and Carol Dove, 2021 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Holmes family (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Early family (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Earsell Jeffreys; Nora Hicks (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - John Adams family (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Brown family (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Catherine Peebles Peoples (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Open letter to the Director of the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts regarding the future of the former site of the Lee Statue (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Research Assistance (Box 5)
  Research Assistance contains articles, census records and slave schedules, genealogical records, marriage records, and other documents providing information on John Holt Rice, as well as the Anderson, Blunk, Finchum, Morton, Rice, and Taylor families.
  - Reverend John Holt Rice and Morton and Rice families (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Anderson family (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Blunk and Finchum families (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Taylor family, including African-Virginians and the Vernacular Building Tradition in Richmond City, 1790-1860 by Gregg Kimball, Perspectives in Vernacular Architecture volume 4, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Davenport (Box 5)
  Davenport includes articles, biographies, census records, death records, genealogies, and other records concerning Isaac Davenport, Jr., and family members, as well as information on Davenport and Company. Records concern Davenport's personal and business involvement with slavery.
  - Isaac Davenport, Jr., (1814-1896) and family (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Davenport and Company (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - National Register of Historic Places--multiple property documentation form (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Enslaved persons in Richmond listing from Journal of Negro History (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Isaac Davenport census records and slave schedules, 1850-1880 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Black Davenports census records, 1870 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- General (Box 5-6)
  General contains articles, brochures, correspondence, emails, poems, presentations, programs, songs, and other documents regarding Richmond Hill, Shockoe Bottom, education, enslaved persons, racism and antiracism, reparations, religion and spirituality, and other topics.
  - Email correspondence with Elizabeth Varon, March 2021 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - On to Richmond" section on touring the city from the Richmond Times-Dispatch, 26 September 2010 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Thomas Fortune Ryan biography (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - History of St. Francis of Assisi Parish: Part 4: Parish Growth and Priestly Vocations (1900-1930s) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Richmond Hill: A Priest's Vision by the Reverend Benjamin P. Campbell, Episcopalian, Chaplain to the Bishop of Virginai, Priest-in_Residence, St. Paul's, Richmond (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Steeped in Prayer: People Come to Richmond Hill for Retreat--But Not for Escape in Virginia Episcopalian, May-June 1998 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Richmond Hill's daily cycle of prayer (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Feelings--color wheel; 4-way Prayer of Forgiveness; composite list of types of traumatic events (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - A Litany for the Healing of Generations (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - African Ubuntu Bible Study (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Cycle of Liberation and Cycle of Socialization (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Article on Shockoe Bottom (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Virginia Secession Ordinance (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Koinonia Slave Trail Walk reflection sheet, 16 November 2019 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Executive Order Number Thirty-Two (Governor Ralph Northam): Establishment of the Commission to Examine Racial Inequity in Virginia Law, 4 June 2019 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Harvard Divinity School interview with Professor Cornel West, 4 December 2017 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Faith in the City by DeBorah J. Cannady, 20 January 2020 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Becoming Anti-Racist--Zones (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - The Art of Hospitality: African Style, by Del Chinchen, 1 October 2001 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - On Reparations, Let Impacted Communities Lead the Way by David Ragland, Melinda Salazar, and Tarell Kyles, 17 October 2019 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - John Brown's Declaration and Constitution from The Intellectual Devotional.com, 11 August 2008 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Letter from Historic Richmond to Kim Chen, Office of the DCAO (Deputy Chief Administrative Officer), Economic Development and Planning, and Maritza Pechin, Manager, Office of Equitable Development, Department of Planning and Development Review, regarding the draft of the Shockoe SMall Area Plan dated July 19, 2021, 16 August 2021 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Sitting on the Sidelines: The Historic Richmond Foundation Declines to Weigh in on the Shockoe Bottome Debate by Ned Oliver, 1 July 2014 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Songs: Canticle of the Turning, Cast Out, O Christ, Wonderful Words of Life Spirit, Pour Out, and Sanctus (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Poems (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Prayer for Discernment and Wisdom When You Need God's Direction (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Black Dancers and Robert E. Lee Monument (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence and papers (Box 6, Folder 1)